Guide to the KZSU Project South Interviews
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
KZSU Project South interviews
1965-1976
SC0066
Becker, Mary Kay.
Dalrymple, Mark David
Dankert, Roger.
Gillam, Richard Arthur.
KZSU (Radio station: Stanford, Calif.)
McRae, James Dean.
Niland, Penelope.
Roise, Jonathan Harold., 1945-2012
Stanford University. Institute of American History
Wells, Judith Lee.
7 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Richard Gillam and KZSU, 1969.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Alternative Formats
The transcripts and audio recordings have been digitized and are available for online review by clicking on the hyperlinks under each interview.
Location of Originals
Original audiotapes are held in the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound.
Historical Note
During the summer of 1965, eight students from Stanford University spent ten weeks in the southern states tape-recording information on the civil rights movement. The eight interviewers -- Mary Kay Becker, Mark Dalrymple, Roger Dankert, Richard Gillam, James McRae, Penny Niland, Jon Roise, and Julie Wells -- were sponsored by KZSU, Stanford's student radio station, and their original intent was to gather material suitable for rebroadcasting in the form of radio programs. Much attention was focused on white civil rights workers, although a great deal of other documentation relevant to black history was also obtained: the interviewers visited over fifty civil rights projects in six states (see appendix) and secured three hundred and thirty hours of recordings, including over two hundred hours of personal interviews. In addition to interviewing members of various, well-known civil rights groups -- the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party (MFDP), the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC), and the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC or `Snick') -- the student interviewers also recorded the formal and the informal remarks of those working with smaller, independent civil rights projects, of local blacks associated with the civil rights movement, and of many others including Ku Klux Klansmen and Southerners connected with the Sheriff's Department of Clay County, Mississippi. The interviewers, in addition, spoke with many white volunteers who participated in Snick's `Washington Lobby' (aimed at unseating the all-white Mississippi Congressional Delegation) but who did not actually go south.
Several of the two-man interview teams recorded parts of the Jackson, Bougalusa, Greensboro, Crawfordsville, and West Point demonstrations, and also gathered various other action tapes of civil rights workers canvassing voters, conducting freedom schools, or participating in demonstrations. Finally, the interviewers recorded many mass meetings and gathered much material on the orientation sessions of MFDP in Hattiesburg, Mississippi and of SCLC in Atlanta, Georgia. All of these original tape recordings are now housed in the Library of Recorded Sound, Stanford, California.
The following pages contain transcripts of the majority of recordings mentioned above. It is hoped that these volumes will rescue from obscurity a body of information which we believe can be of great use both to scholars and to laymen interested in the dramatic history of the civil rights movement during the past decade. This material may prove to be especially valuable because it concerns a transitional period between the first `freedom summer' of 1964, the high tide of civil rights, and the `Meredith March of 1966 during which Stokely Carmichael first voiced the compelling cry of `Black Power'. In fact, at least one essay and a documentary history based on these recordings are already in progress, and it is expected that more will soon follow.
Many of the interviewees are identified by name on the first page of the transcripts which follow. Because of the long time which has already elapsed since the interviews were recorded, however, it is requested that these names not be used in print unless the written consent of the interviewees concerned is first obtained.
In closing, we would like to express our thanks to the Stanford Institute of American History and to the Stanford Library for financial support which made possible the transcription of the original recordings. We would also like to thank Mrs. Betty Eldon of the Institute of American History who accepted the added burden of paperwork connected with this transcription project with tolerance and good humor. Finally, we acknowledge a particular debt to Professor George Knoles for his unfailing encouragement and support.
Richard Gillam
James D. McRae
Palo Alto
January 1969
Scope and Content
This collection contains transcribed meetings and interviews with Civil Rights workers in the South recorded by several Stanford students affiliated with the campus radio station KZSU during the summer of 1965. The project was sponsored by the Institute of American History at Stanford. The collection includes information relating to black history; interviews of members of the Congress of Racial Equality, the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, the NAACP, the Southern Christian Leadership Conference, and the Student Non-violent Coordinating Committee; transcripts of formal and informal remarks of persons working with smaller, independent civil rights projects, of local blacks associated with the civil rights movement, and other people, including Ku Klux Klansmen; transcribed action tapes of civil rights workers canvassing voters, conducting freedom schools, or participating in demonstration; speeches by and/or interviews with Ralph David Abernathy, Charles Evers, James Farmer, Martin Luther King, Jr., and Hosea Williams; and a Ku Klux Klan meeting and speech made by Robert Sheldon, its Imperial Wizard.
Access Terms
Abernathy, Ralph David, 1926-1990; Congress of Racial Equality.; Evers, Charles, 1922-; Farmer, James.; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968.; Ku Klux Klan (1915- ); KZSU (Radio station: Stanford, Calif.); McDaniel, Edward L., 1934-2011.; Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party.; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP); Shelton, Robert M., 1929-2003.; Southern Christian Leadership Conference.; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.).; Williams, Hosea.; African Americans--Civil rights--United States.; Audiotapes.; Civil rights movements--United States.; Civil rights--United States.; Interviews.
Collection Contents
- Interviews, 1965
  - White CORE (Congress of Racial Equality) Volunteers
    - Meldon, Acheson, white, male, CORE student summer volunteer, 0290, Ferriday, Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Danbert, ?, white, male, CORE Staff member, 0037 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Anonymous, white, male, CORE volunteer, 0028, Bogalusa, Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Charles [UNK], white, male, CORE student volunteer, 0044 - 1 (side 2), Bogalusa, Louisiana. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Michael Clurman, white, male, CORE volunteer, 0287 (sides 1 and 2), Ferriday, Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mimi Feingold, white, female, CORE student volunteer, 0124-0125 (side 1), Clinton, Louisiana, July 5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Martin Goldstein, white, male, CORE student volunteer, 0123 (side 1 and 2), Clinton Louisiana. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Joan Grieco, white, female, CORE summer volunteer, 0045-1 (side 1), Bogalusa, Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harold Ickes, white, male, CORE summer volunteer, 0353, Tallulah, Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Howard Kaibel, white, male, married, CORE volunteer, 0129 (side 1), Greensburg, La. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Rowena N. Kaibel, white, female, CORE volunteer, 0127 (side 1 and 2), Greensburg, La. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fred Lacey, white, male, 20, CORE, 0126 (side 1 and 2), Greensburg, La. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Donnie Lee, white, female, CORE volunteer, 0044-1 (side 1), Bogalusa, La. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Michael Lesser, white, male, CORE staff, 0284 (side 1 and 2), Baton Rouge, La. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Kathy Miller, white, female, CORE summer volunteer, 0214, Baton Rouge, La. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Lorraine Roy, white, female, CORE summer volunteer, 0211-1 (side 1 and 2) Baton Rouge, La. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Alec Van Sinderen, white, male, CORE student summer volunteer, 0315 (side 1 and 2, cont'd on 0314), Tallulah, La. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - White (M)FDP (Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party) or SNCC (Student Non-violent coordinating Committee) volunteers.
    - Patti Alter, white, female, FDP summer volunteer, 0365 (side 1 and 2, cont'd on 0366, side 1 and part of 2), Quitman, Mississippi. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Anonymous, white, female, SNCC volunteer, [UNK] lobby, 0109, Selma, Alabama (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Anonymous, white, female, SNCC, 0244 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Cal Atwood, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 9001, Indianola, Mississippi (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Eve Bartle, white, female, FDP volunteer (summer) 0138, Hattiesburg (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Edith Black, white, female, FDP summer volunteer, 0219, Natchez, Miss. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Pete Blickeman, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 0217, Natchez, Miss. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Nina Boal, white, female, FDP volunteer, 0360-1 (side 1 and 2, cont'd 0359-2), Quitman, Miss. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Terry Carr, White, Male, SNCC, 0419-1a (side 1, second half of side, and side 2), Arkansas (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Don Chapman, white, Male, FDP summer volunteer, 0358 (sides 1 and 2, and 0359 side 1), Quitman, Miss. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Pat Cohen, white, female, SNCC volunteer, 0110 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Warner Drexel, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 9000 (sides 1 and 2), Indianola, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Dave Farley, white, male, SNCC volunteer for Washington lobby, 0065, Indianola, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Mitch Gerfield, white, male, MFDP volunteer, 0291, Natchez, Mississippi (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Bob Gilman, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 0237 (side 1 and 2), Tibbee, Miss. (Clay Co.) (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Jo Green, white, female, FDP summer volunteer, 0263 (side 1 and 2, cont'd on 0261) Aberdeen, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bert Halprin, white, male, FDP student volunteer, 0239 (side 1 and 2), Clay Co. Miss. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Bill Hansen, white, male, SNCC staff member, 0416- (sides 1 and 2) Arkansas (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Caroline Hills, white, female, from England, FDP summer volunteer, 9003 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Randy Ireson, white, male, FDP student volunteer, 0163 (side 1 and 2), West point, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - S. Jones, SNCC, 0419 (side 1), Arkansas (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - James Kates, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 0218, Natchez, Mississippi (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Louis King, white, male, FDP volunteer, 9012, Cleveland, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Susan Levin, white, female, FDP summer volunteer, 0242, Whites, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Jay Lockard, white, female, FDP student volunteer, 0162 (side 1), West Point, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Pat McGauley, white, female, SNCC volunteer, 0405 (sides 1 and 2), Laurel, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Mike Maller, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 9007 (side 1 and 2), Indianola, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Nancy Myron, white, female, FDP volunteer (non-studen 0260, West Point, Mississippi (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Chip Neville, white, male, FDP volunteer, 0309 (side 1 and 2), Vicksburg, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Ben Ovshinsky, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 0268 (side 1 and 2, cont'd on 0261), Section, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Lincoln Pain, white, male, FDP student volunteer, 0236 (side 1 and 2), Tibbee, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Velma Parness, white, female, FDP summer [UNK], 9002 (side 1 and 2), Indianola, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Paddy Quick, white, female, (English), FDP, 0238-1, Clay County, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - John Rapp, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 0259 (side 1 and 2, cont'd on side 2, 0258), West Point, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Michael Reuss, white, male, FDP student volunteer, 0257 (side 1 and 2, plus 0258), Section, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - David Ruff, white, male, FDP volunteer, 0241, Clay County, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Bill Rusk, White, male, FDP summer volunteer, 0312, Vicksburg, Miss. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Joyce Schurick, white, female, FDP summer volunteer 9006 (side 1 and 2), Ruleville, Mississippi (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Alex Shimkin, white, male, FDP summer volunteer, 0050, Jackson, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Bill Simons, white, male, 0326 (sides 1 and 2) Batesville, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - D. Smith, female, white, Student volunteer - indepedent - SNCC? 0147 (side 1 and 2), Selma. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Mark Smith, white male, FDP student volunteer, 0262 - 1 (sides 1 and 2), Aberdeen, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Frank Sorocco, 0406 and 0407, Laurel, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Melinda Summerall, white, female, FDP summer volunteer, 0234, Whites, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - David Tobis, white male, FDP volunteer, 0160 (side and 2), Whites, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Eugene Turitz, white, male, MFDP volunteer, 0325-1 (sides 1 and 2), Batesville, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Nancy Jo Turitz, white, female, MFDP volunteer, 0325-1 (sides 1 and 2), Batesville, Miss. (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - White SCLC - SCOPE (Southern Christian Leadership Conference - Southern Community and Political Education Project) volunteers
    - Maggie Anderson, white, female, SCOPE student volunteer, 0228 (side 1 and 2), Marion, Alabama (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Anonymous, white, female, SCOPE volunteer 0424 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Anonymous, female, civil rights worker, 0192-13 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Anonymous, female, white, SCOPE volunteer, 0174, Macon, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Anonymous, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0269-1 (sides 1 and 2) Crawfordsville, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Anonymous, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0059 (side 1 and 2) Luverne, Ala. (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Anonymous, white, male, SCLC, 1090 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Dan Boylan, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0066, 6/19/65 done at SCLC orientation (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Bob Brumbaugh, white, male, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0279 (sides 1 and 2), Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Larry Cloyd, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0224 (sides 1 and 2), Macon, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Joseph R. Cooney (priest), white, male, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0274 (sides 1 and 2), Crawfordsville, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Barbara Enaney, white, female, SCOPE volunteer, 0152 (sides 1 and 2), Midway, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Paula Ferrari, white, female, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0055-1 (side 1), Luverne, Alabama (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Joseph Goldberg, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0182 (side 1 and 2), Macon, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Bruce Hartford, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0150 (sides 1 and 2), Laverne, Alabama, Freedom Home (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Diane Hirsch, white, female, SCOPE Volunteer, 0181 (sides 1 and 2), Macon, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Carol Johnson, white, female, SCOPE volunteer, 0221-1 (sides 1 and 2), Macon, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Richard Klausner, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0056, Luverne, Alabama (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Richard Krushnic, white, male, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0060 (sides 1 and 2), Luverne, Ala. (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Willy Leventhal, white, male, SCOPE student volunteer, 0180 and 0179, (side 2), Macon, Georgia. (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Edith Needleman, white female, SCOPE volunteer, 0183 (sides 1 and 2), Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Sarah L. Oakes, white, female, 0184, Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Nan Ohlinger, white, female, SCLC - SCOPE student volunteer, 0178 (sides 1 and 2), Macon, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Steve Press, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0193, Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Neil Reichline, white male, SCOPE student volunteer, 0176 - 1, Macon, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Sheldon Rosen, white male, SCOPE volunteer, 0277, Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Barbara Rothkring, white, female, SCOPE, 0280 (sides 1 and 2), Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Peggy Rozga, white, female, SCOPE volunteer, 0151 (sides 1 and 2), Union Springs, Ala. (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Patricia Ryan, white, female, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0275, Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Mickey Shur, white, male, SCOPE volunteer, 0276 (sides 1 and 2), Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Joel Siegal, white, male, SCOPE student volunteer, 0223, Macon, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - James Simons, white, male, SCLC student volunteer, 0177 (sides 1 and 2), Macon, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - David Soakne, white, male, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0057, Luverne, Alabama (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Cary Stone, white, female, SCOPE student volunteer, 0227-1 (sides 1 and 2), Marion, Ala. (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Judy Van Allen, white, female, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0271 (sides 1 and 2), Crawfordsville, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Candi Weber, White, female, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0270 (side 2), Crawfordsville, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Janet Wolfe, white, female, SCOPE summer volunteer, 0046 (sides 1 and 2), Greenville, Ala. (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Elian Zukerman, white, male, SCLC volunteer - head of project, 0197, Columbia, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Elaine Zvondin, white, female, SCOPE volunteer, 0220 (sides 1 and 2), Macon, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Earl Coblyn, white, male, SCOPE, 0278 (sides 1 and 2), Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - White SNCC volunteers for Washington Lobby, interviewed in Washington, D.C.
    - Margot Adler, white, female, SNCC Washington Lobby, 0033 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Anonymous, white, female, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0106 (side 2) (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Anonymous, white, female, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0034 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Anonymous, white, male, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0039 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Anonymous, white, male, FDP for Washington Lobby, 0030 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Anonymous, white, male, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0120 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Tim Carrell, white, male, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0036-1 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Robert Foley, white, male, SNCC student volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0038 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Michael Gardner, white, male, SNCC lobby in Washington volunteer, 0031 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Eugene Kettner, white, male, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0029 (sides 1 and 2), Afe 15 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - John Pocelli, white, male, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0032 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - John Wardlow, white, male, SNCC volunteer for Washington Lobby, 0038A (sides 1 and 2) (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - D. Williams, white, male, volunteer for SNCC for Lobby in Washington, 0035 (side 1) (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - White independent volunteers
    - Hilda Brauerman, white, female, Medical Committee for Human Rights: student volunteer, 0212-1 (side 1), Baton Rouge, Louisiana. (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Judith Dunlap, white, female, Selma Free College, 0145 (side 1) (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Chuck Fagen, white, male, Director of Selma Free College, 0388 (side 1 and 2), 0336 (side 1 and 10 minutes of side 2) (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Chuck Foger, white, male, SCLC Free College, 0148 (sides 1 and 2), Selma, Alabama (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - William Lacero, white, male, Southern Teaching Program, 0186, Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Efram Lipkin, white, male, 0153 (side 1), Tougaloo, Mississippi (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Peter Nash, white, male, student volunteer for medical committee for Human Rights, 0107 (side 1 Louisiana. (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Dave Sowd, white, male, independent, 9014-1 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Mary Varela, white, female, independent literacy project, 0411 (side 1 and 2), Mr. Beulah, Miss. (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Mr. Williamson, White, male, Selma College, 0146 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Al Zeigler, white, male, American Friends Service Committee, 0187, Orangeburg, South Carolina. (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Black CORE volunteers and staff, local, Louisiana Blacks
    - Jimmie Andrews, Negro, male, CORE volunteer, 0282 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Anonymous, Negro, female, CORE volunteer, 0281, Baton Rouge, Louisiana. (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Anonymous, Negro, local person in Bogalusa, Louisiana, 0048 (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Anonymous, Negro, male, CORE volunteer in Bogalusa, Louisiana, 0028 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Anonymous, Negro, male, CORE staff, 0125 (side 2) (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Henry Austin, Negro, male, CORE volunteer, 0333 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - James Bell, Negro, male, Local volunteer for CORE, 0121 (sides 1 and 2), Clinton, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Henry Brown, Negro, male, CORE staff, 0120, Clinton, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Herman Carter, Negro, male, Member of SSOC and possibly SNCC, working for CORE, 0213 (side 1), Baton Rouge, sLouisiana (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Artis Ray Dawson, Negro, male, CORE local volunteer, 0335 (sides 1 and 2), Tallulah, La. (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - David Dennis, Negro, male, Director of Southern Regional CORE, 0442-1 (cont'd on 0443, all sides New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Charlotte B. Greenup, Negro, female, local person, 0122 (side 1), Clinton, La. (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Archie Hunter, Negro, male, CORE summer volunteer, 0286, Ferriday, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - George Noflin, Negro, male, CORE - head of local chapter, 0131, St. Francisville, Louisiana. (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - James Peters, Negro, male, CORE summer volunteer, 0210, Baton Rouge, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Michael Robinson, Negro, male, CORE volunteer, 0283 (side 1) (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Ernestina Vanderpool, Negro, female, CORE student volunteer, 0045-1 (side 2), Bogalusa, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - James "Mice" Williams, Negro, male, CORE local volunteer, 0313, Tallulah, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Zelma Wyche, Negro, male, Head of local voters' league, 0352 (sides 1 and 2), Tallulah, La. (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Black MFDP - SNCC volunteers and staff, local Mississippi blacks
    - Otis Brown, Negro, male, FDP project leader, 9004 (sides 1 and 2), Indianola, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - John Buffington, Negro, male, Project leader of Clay County for Mississippi FDP, member of SNCC, 0165 and 0162 (side 2) (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Warner Buxton, Negro, male, FDP: assistant project leader, 0357, (sides 1 and 2), Quitman, Mississip (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Sam Carr, Negro, male, leader FDP - ex-com, 0234 (sides 1 and 2), Aberdeen, Mississippi. (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Virginia Collins, Negro, female, Louisiana FDP Chairman, 0367 (sides 1 and 2, 0368, side 1), New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Annie Devine, negro, female, FDP: member of ex. com, 0488 (sides 1 and 2, and 0489, side 1), Canton, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 153)